<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Adderall on Virtualbeck&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/tags/adderall/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Adderall on Virtualbeck&#39;s Blog</description>
    <image>
      <title>Virtualbeck&#39;s Blog</title>
      <url>https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/13488662</url>
      <link>https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/13488662</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.140.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.virtualbeck.com/tags/adderall/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>empathy pills</title>
      <link>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/posts/empathy-pills/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/posts/empathy-pills/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All my life, I&amp;rsquo;ve never shown an immense amount of empathy. Whether that is a product of nature or nurture, I&amp;rsquo;d say nature. My parents love me and we have a great relationship. I&amp;rsquo;m naturally curious and concerned about others&amp;rsquo; feelings, but often I have a cold pragmatic response to emotional output. This has remained a constant throughout my life.. up until I started taking adderall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, for me, was the year of caffeine. Mike on caffeine was like Mike+. I could do more work, get it done faster, and &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; better physically. Have you heard of Monster energy drinks? Of course you have. You can probably even picture the Monster logo in your mind right now. It&amp;rsquo;s very heavily marketed. The sugar-free drink of choice contains 150mg of caffeine. Based on the product&amp;rsquo;s webpage for my favorite lime green drink in question - Ultra Paradise, it&amp;rsquo;s flavor profile is &lt;code&gt;Kiwi Lime with a hint of Cucumber&lt;/code&gt;. I don&amp;rsquo;t know about that. It has always tasted like a green apple jolly rancher to me. Anyway, with 2 coffees and an Ultra Paradise down the hatch, it was game on. I was hooked on the feeling of ~300mg of caffeine pumping through my body.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
