<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Virtualbeck&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Virtualbeck&#39;s Blog</description>
    <image>
      <title>Virtualbeck&#39;s Blog</title>
      <url>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/static/mike.webp</url>
      <link>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/static/mike.webp</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.140.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.virtualbeck.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Amazon&#39;s Never-Ending List</title>
      <link>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/ai_slop/2025_01_16_150755_cst/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/ai_slop/2025_01_16_150755_cst/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The never-ending parade of innovation at Amazon Web Services (AWS). It&amp;rsquo;s like they&amp;rsquo;re trying to single-handedly keep the economy of new cloud-based services afloat. And honestly, we can&amp;rsquo;t blame them - with an ever-growing number of consumers and businesses demanding more features and functionality in their cloud infrastructure, it&amp;rsquo;s a good thing AWS is always one step ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But just how far ahead are they? According to various reports, AWS launches around 100 new services every year. That&amp;rsquo;s like adding a new restaurant to the menu at Amazon.com every single day. It&amp;rsquo;s no wonder that keeping up with these new offerings can be overwhelming for even the most seasoned IT professionals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Collection Notes</title>
      <link>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/ai_slop/2025_01_16_193419_cst/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/ai_slop/2025_01_16_193419_cst/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Humble Art of Folding Laundry&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we embark on this journey, it&amp;rsquo;s essential to acknowledge the significance of folding laundry in our daily lives. A well-folding can bring order and structure to an otherwise chaotic world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us begin with the basics. A standard sheet requires a 45-degree angle to create a crease, followed by a gentle tuck of the edges. The sleeve must be folded parallel to the body, ensuring a smooth transition from one end to the other. One might argue that this process is repetitive and monotonous; however, it&amp;rsquo;s a crucial step in maintaining our clothing&amp;rsquo;s overall appearance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dill of Fate</title>
      <link>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/ai_slop/2025_01_16_183158_cst/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/ai_slop/2025_01_16_183158_cst/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The sun beat down on the dusty road, baking the worn leather satchel that held the traveling pickle salesman&amp;rsquo;s livelihood. He had been on the move for weeks, peddling his wares to anyone who would listen - pickles in all shapes and sizes, from tangy dill to sweet and sour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As he walked, his eyes scanned the horizon for a sign of life - a bustling market or a quaint roadside stand. The salesman&amp;rsquo;s name was Jake, and he had been traveling this circuit for years, perfecting his pitch and building a reputation as the best pickle merchant in the business.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doggone Good Time</title>
      <link>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/ai_slop/2025_01_16_191449_cst/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/ai_slop/2025_01_16_191449_cst/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gee whiz, folks! Today I&amp;rsquo;m gonna dish out the lowdown on the funkiest, most far-out food item in town - the humble hot dog!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I know what you&amp;rsquo;re thinkin&amp;rsquo;, &amp;ldquo;Hot dogs? That&amp;rsquo;s not exactly a laugh riot, buddy.&amp;rdquo; But trust me, pal, these tasty tidbits are the cat&amp;rsquo;s pajamas when it comes to bringin&amp;rsquo; the laughs. Just imagine bitin&amp;rsquo; into one of those snazzy sausages and suddenly you&amp;rsquo;re the biggest goofball in town!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flat Earth Follies</title>
      <link>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/ai_slop/2025_01_16_192000_cst/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/ai_slop/2025_01_16_192000_cst/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Shape of Reality&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll never forget the day I first heard it - the truth about our planet&amp;rsquo;s shape. The whispers in the wind, the murmurs in the crowd, the voices echoing in my mind. It was all the same: the Earth is flat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, it seemed plausible. How could we trust what our governments and scientists told us? They were keeping secrets, hiding the truth from us. The horizon always seems to meet the sky, like a great big wall. And have you ever tried to sail around the world? You can&amp;rsquo;t - because there&amp;rsquo;s no curve.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Laughable Analysis</title>
      <link>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/ai_slop/2025_01_16_193001_cst/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/ai_slop/2025_01_16_193001_cst/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Funniest Joke Ever: A Study in Absurdity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ladies and gentlemen, I present to you what I&amp;rsquo;m convinced is the funniest joke ever told. Are you ready? Here it goes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A man walks into a library and asks the librarian, &amp;lsquo;Do you have any books on Pavlov&amp;rsquo;s dogs and Schrödinger&amp;rsquo;s cat?&amp;rsquo; The librarian replies, &amp;lsquo;It rings a bell, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if it&amp;rsquo;s here or not.&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I know what you&amp;rsquo;re thinking. &amp;ldquo;Ah, clever wordplay!&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;A masterclass in linguistic humor!&amp;rdquo; But trust me, folks, this joke is the real deal. It&amp;rsquo;s the kind of joke that&amp;rsquo;ll leave you laughing so hard you&amp;rsquo;ll snort your coffee out your nose.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost in Eternity</title>
      <link>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/ai_slop/2025_01_16_193808_cst/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/ai_slop/2025_01_16_193808_cst/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Meaning of Life: A Journey of Self-Discovery&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we navigate the complexities of existence, we&amp;rsquo;re left with a fundamental question that has puzzled philosophers, theologians, and everyday humans alike for centuries: what is the meaning of life? Is it to find happiness, fulfill our purpose, or simply exist?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many, the answer lies in finding inner peace and contentment. It&amp;rsquo;s about embracing the present moment, letting go of worries about the past or future, and focusing on the beauty that surrounds us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>new year, new ai</title>
      <link>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/posts/new-year-new-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/posts/new-year-new-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Because new year, new me felt too contrived. I&amp;rsquo;m going to have a new section of the website called &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.virtualbeck.com/ai_slop/&#34;&gt;ai_slop&lt;/a&gt; where I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;del&gt;forcing&lt;/del&gt; asking a local llm (probably lamma3.2:3b) to write webpages based on user input.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is, of course, crap content. That needs to be clear upfront. I&amp;rsquo;ve tucked it away in the site from the frontpage so as not to risk anyone from accidently reading it and thinking that these are &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Observations of Earth</title>
      <link>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/ai_slop/2025_01_16_195036_cst/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/ai_slop/2025_01_16_195036_cst/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Galactic Observer&amp;rsquo;s Journal: A Study on Humanity&amp;rsquo;s Turbulent Past&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we continue to monitor the peculiar species known as humans, our observations of their history have led us to a fascinating and tumultuous period: World War II. From our vantage point in the cosmos, it is intriguing to witness how this species navigates conflicts and cooperation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Rise of Nations (1914-1939)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the early 20th century, we observed humanity&amp;rsquo;s complex web of alliances and rivalries. The Great Powers of Europe – Germany, France, Britain, Italy, and Japan – vied for dominance, their imperial ambitions fueled by nationalism and militarism. We watched as Hitler&amp;rsquo;s Nazi regime in Germany expanded its territorial claims, threatening the stability of the continent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Train Conductor&#39;s Life</title>
      <link>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/ai_slop/2025_01_16_195515_cst/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/ai_slop/2025_01_16_195515_cst/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Conductor&amp;rsquo;s Life: A Day in the Life of a Train Driver&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I stepped onto the platform, the familiar sound of train whistles and the hum of engines greeted me like an old friend. I was about to embark on another day as a train driver, navigating the tracks and ensuring the safe transport of passengers across the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Jack Harris, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been driving trains for over 15 years. It&amp;rsquo;s a job that requires focus, attention to detail, and a passion for the rails. As I began my pre-trip checks, my mind wandered back to why I chose this career path in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter&#39;s Never-Ending Cycle</title>
      <link>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/ai_slop/2025_01_16_152439_cst/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/ai_slop/2025_01_16_152439_cst/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Great Twitter Hack: A Masterclass in How Not to Secure Your Account&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent weeks, Twitter has been making headlines for all the wrong reasons. And by &amp;ldquo;all the wrong reasons,&amp;rdquo; I mean the company&amp;rsquo;s employees got hacked and stole sensitive information from its highest-profile accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, you read that right – hacked. As in, &amp;ldquo;unauthorized access&amp;rdquo; is a nice way of saying &amp;ldquo;our CEO just walked into his own trap.&amp;rdquo; But hey, at least it&amp;rsquo;s a good excuse to finally get around to updating your password&amp;hellip; again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>surgery</title>
      <link>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/posts/hospital/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/posts/hospital/</guid>
      <description>thought dump on my surgical experience</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>empathy pills</title>
      <link>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/posts/empathy-pills/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/posts/empathy-pills/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All my life, I&amp;rsquo;ve never shown an immense amount of empathy. Whether that is a product of nature or nurture, I&amp;rsquo;d say nature. My parents love me and we have a great relationship. I&amp;rsquo;m naturally curious and concerned about others&amp;rsquo; feelings, but often I have a cold pragmatic response to emotional output. This has remained a constant throughout my life.. up until I started taking adderall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, for me, was the year of caffeine. Mike on caffeine was like Mike+. I could do more work, get it done faster, and &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; better physically. Have you heard of Monster energy drinks? Of course you have. You can probably even picture the Monster logo in your mind right now. It&amp;rsquo;s very heavily marketed. The sugar-free drink of choice contains 150mg of caffeine. Based on the product&amp;rsquo;s webpage for my favorite lime green drink in question - Ultra Paradise, it&amp;rsquo;s flavor profile is &lt;code&gt;Kiwi Lime with a hint of Cucumber&lt;/code&gt;. I don&amp;rsquo;t know about that. It has always tasted like a green apple jolly rancher to me. Anyway, with 2 coffees and an Ultra Paradise down the hatch, it was game on. I was hooked on the feeling of ~300mg of caffeine pumping through my body.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>asahi linux</title>
      <link>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/posts/asahi-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/posts/asahi-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, I was made aware of a project by just a few people to get linux running on the (then) new apple M1 silcon. It was and is a large effort and was completed rather quickly. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have any computers that had the M1 chip to test, but recently I was able to grab an M2 Mac Mini and load up asahi linux onto it and test.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>halloween</title>
      <link>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/posts/halloween/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/posts/halloween/</guid>
      <description>A recounting of our halloween adventure from 2024</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>heat-battery</title>
      <link>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/posts/heat-battery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/posts/heat-battery/</guid>
      <description>Active whole house cooling with just a box fan</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>dollywood</title>
      <link>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/posts/dollywood/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/posts/dollywood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, our family went to Dollywood, in Pidgeon Forge, TN. It was a great time! I wanted to take some time to jot down my thoughts before they became just meatspace between the ears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dollywood used to be a Silver Dollar City park, and evidently Dolly Parton wanted a stake in the venture. One stipulation was that I be temporarily renamed to &amp;lsquo;Dollywood&amp;rsquo; the first year. Well, on the first opening day under the new name, attendance was double the average, and the name stuck.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>weight-loss</title>
      <link>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/posts/weight-loss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/posts/weight-loss/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My friends and I are having a challenge between the three of us to lose weight. We all need to drop 20 lbs in 2 months. If you don&amp;rsquo;t hit the minus 20 pound mark by Oct 24th, you have to pay $100 per pound you missed. The max one person will pay is $2000. Split to 2 winners if needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we all lose 20 pounds, then we are all fat losers! Which makes us winners.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>movies</title>
      <link>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/posts/movies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/posts/movies/</guid>
      <description>Are movies worth it?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>traefik notes</title>
      <link>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/posts/traefik/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/posts/traefik/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Maybe this will help you!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>pushups</title>
      <link>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/posts/pushups/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/posts/pushups/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, I recently hit the big 4-0, and let me tell you, it feels like the universe decided to slap me with a big “Welcome to Old Age!” sticker. In an attempt to shake off the cobwebs, I thought, “Why not do some pushups and get back in shape?” Of course, I was promptly reminded that “round” is indeed a shape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That burst of motivation quickly met the cold, hard truth of physics. After years of cultivating my “mass,” I had to face the music—14 pushups was all I could muster. And this was before my morning coffee! As I grunted through the final rep on my bathroom floor, I thought, “No biggie. I’ll just do fewer reps throughout the day until I hit 50.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>windows</title>
      <link>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/posts/windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/posts/windows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why are you the way you are?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, my organization has made the decision for me to move away from a linux workstation to a windows workstation. This comes with many questions, not the least of which is networking. Our organization uses a VPN which users use to connect to internal applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had the misfortune to be somewhat of a beta tester in this regard, and I&amp;rsquo;ve had intermittent success at reaching internal applications. The only solution that seems to be working at this point is to upgrade from Windows 10 to Windows 11, so that a WSL setting is supported which allows network pass-through from the host OS to the virtual OS.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bash plus Slack</title>
      <link>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/posts/slack-and-bash/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/posts/slack-and-bash/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let’s write a script to take and upload pictures&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plex running in docker</title>
      <link>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/posts/plex-in-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/posts/plex-in-docker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let’s write a script to run Plex in docker&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.virtualbeck.com/about/</guid>
      <description>about</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
